Brian Adams

brian@brianadams.codes

937.602.8325

Website: brianadams.codes

Github: @badams2527

Permanent Residence:

Kettering, OH

Current Residence:

Cincinnati, OH

Summary

Educated, efficient, self-motivated software developer with a wide range of past experience in various technologies. Strong communication skills allow for clients and co-workers to pose a problem and get a clear, effective solution in return. Able to gauge a situation from all different angles, and select the proper technology and implementation by not being "tied down" to any single one.

Education

University of Cincinnati (2012 – Current)

- Current GPA: 3.22
- Bachelor of Science in Computer Science
- Expected Graduation: 2017

Work Experience

Rippe & Kingston Systems, Inc. (October 2013 – Current)

- Lead developer on a large reporting application which was scalable and distributed using Python/Flask, RethinkDB, and AngularJS
- Accepted responsibility for multiple projects when the project manager left
- Exercised several skills in multiple projects requiring different skills
- Collaborated with small team to build and maintain large-scale web applications
- Manage time effectively while working part-time during school

ENSE (March 2012 – Current)

- Food equipment buying group in the UK
- Sole developer for the company <u>www.enseuk.co.uk</u>
- Design and develop entire web application from the ground up
- Use Node.JS, AngularJS, and RethinkDB to deliver a highly customizable and extensible user experience
- Interact with multiple people in the UK

Reynolds and Reynolds (April 2013 - August 2013)

- First professional corporate experience
- Developed internal web applications and WinForms applications using C#, JavaScript, and VB
- Gained experience in version control software (Microsoft Visual SourceSafe and SVN)

Activities

Theta Chi Fraternity (2013 – Current)

- Founding Father
- Alumni Relations Chairman (Fall 2014)
- Standards Board Chairman (Spring 2015)

ACM@UC

- UC chapter of ACM
- Member of the Web Development Team
- Member of the ICPC Programming Team

Languages:

- Python
- JavaScript
- C#
- HTML
- CSS
- SOL

Software/Frameworks:

- AngularJS
- Flask
- RethinkDB
- Node.JS
- ASP.NET
- SQL Server
- jQuery

Version Control:

- Git
- Subversion